Louis Lozowick
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Organizations, 1930-1972, Series 5:; (Box 4; 0.4 linear ft.; Reel 5898)
  - American Artists' Congress (Box 4, Reel 5898)
    - Printed Matter, 1936-1942, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 313-358)
  - American Council for a Democratic Greece, 1948 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 359-361)
  - An American Group, Inc., 1939-1941, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 362-382)
  - American Society for Race Tolerance, 1939 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 383-386)
  - American Writers Conference, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 387-388)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1948-1966 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 389-405)
  - Artists Equity Association of New Jersey, Inc., 1961-1971, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 406-426)
  - Associated Artists of New Jersey, 1948, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 427-433)
  - Association des écrivians et des artistes révolutionnaires (Section française de l'U.I.E.R.), n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 434-448)
  - Conference on Jewish Youth, 1940 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 449-453)
  - Federal Arts Committee, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 454-458)
  - Foreign Language Information Service, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 459-465)
  - Jewish People's Fraternal Order, Million Dollar Rehabilitation Fund, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 466-468)
  - John Reed Club (Box 4, Reel 5898)
    - Constitution, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 469-474)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1935, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 475-605)
    - First National Conference, May 29-30, 1932 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 606-617)
    - Minutes, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 618-648)
    - Miscellaneous Items, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 649-654)
    - Printed Matter, 1931-1935 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 655-666)
  - The Meeting Place, 1930 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 667-669)
  - Municipal Art Committee, City of New York, 1936-1939, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 670-701)
  - National Committee for People's Rights, 1939 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 702-703)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., Art Committee, 1944-1945, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 704-717)
  - National Council on Art in Jewish Life, 1965, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 718-724)
  - New-Age Gallery, Inc., 1946 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 725-727)
  - New York City Council for Art Week, 1940, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 728-736)
  - Print Makers Society of California, 1932 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 737-741)
  - Society of American Graphic Artists, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 742-754)
  - United American Artists, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 755-761)
  - United May Day Provisional Committee, 1939 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 762-764)
  - World Alliance for Jewish Culture, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 765-766)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 767-783)
- Printed Material, 1920-1974, Series 6:; (Boxes 4-5 and OV 7; 1.25 linear ft.; Reel 5898-5899)
  Miscellaneous items include research materials collected by Lozowick for his writings, along with a variety of clippings and articles on art-related and other subjects probably used for the same purpose. Illustrations of artists at work, in their studios, galleries, etc. include photographs, reproductions, and clippings. Also of interest is a 1922 broadside in French and Russian announcing a lecture.
  In addition to the exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations housed here, Series 4: Business Records includes a smaller number of checklists, announcements, etc. filed with Lozowick's alphabetical record of works exhibited and consigned.
  This series is arranged into 4 subseries:
  6.1: Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations
  6.2: By Lozowick
  6.3: About Lozowick
  6.4: Miscellaneous Items
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations, 1922-1973, 6.1:
    - Announcements and Invitations, Lozowick Exhibitions, 1939-1974, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 786-829)
    - Catalogs of Lozowick Exhibitions, 1922-1973, n.d., (13 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 830-1185)
    - Catalogs of Other Exhibitions, 1926-1974, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 1186-1221)
    - Prospectuses, 1936-1973 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 1222-1240)
  - By Lozowick, 1922-1947, 6.2:
    - Articles, 1922-1930, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1243-1292)
    - Book, Modern Russian Art, Museum of Modern Art, Société Anonyme, Inc., 1925 (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1293-1328)
    - Book Reviews, 1927-1947 (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1329-1343)
    - Illustrations, 1925-1929 (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1344-1350)
    - Reproductions, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1351-1353)
  - About Lozowick, 1923-1974, 6.3:
    - Announcements of Lectures; Course Syllabus; Brochure about Summer Tour, 1920-1936, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1355-1386)
    - Articles, 1923-1973, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5898, Frame 1387-1450)
    - Clippings, 1924-1973, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 12-40)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1974, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 41-50)
  - Miscellaneous Items, 1922-1971, 6.4:
    - Broadside (in French and Russian), 1922 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 53-55)
    - Clippings and Articles (Box 5, Reel 5899)
      - American Artists' Congress, 1935-1940, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 56-64)
      - Contemporary Indian Artists (series in Design), 1958 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 65-131)
      - Jewish Art, 1932-1967, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 132-213)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects (art related), 1942-1971, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 214-252)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects (not art related), 1931-1972, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 253-271)
      - Unidentified (in Russian and Yiddish), 1959, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 272-316)
    - Illustrations of Artists at Work, in their Studios, Galleries, etc., n.d., (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 317-533)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (art related), 1939-1947, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 534-592)
    - Picture Post Cards (blank), n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 593-598)
    - Reproductions (Box 5, Reel 5899)
      - A-Z, and Unidentified, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 599-663)
      - Soviet Art, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 664-699)
    - Research Material [for "the Jew In Art"?], 1923-1945, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 700-776)
    - Research Material for Lozowick's Writings on Russian Art and Artists, 1925-1954, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 777-1099)
    - Research Material for "Solomon Nunes Carvalho," 1952 (Box OV 7, Reel 5899, Frame 1100-1112)
- Sketches, n.d., Series 7:; (Box 5; 1 folder; Reel 5899)
  Ink and pencil sketches include figures, geometric abstractions, landscapes, side view of Solomon's Temple, and a scale drawing of a panel elevation. Three items are mere doodles.
  - Sketches, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1113-1137)
- Photographs, 1898-1973, Series 8:; (Boxes 5-6; 1.25 linear ft.; Reel 5899)
  Images of Lozowick include a photograph of him as a young child, along with pictures of his father, wife Adele and son Lee, and a portrait thought to be of David Burliuk. Of particular interest is a photograph of Lozowick participating in a demonstration organized by the John Reed Club and Artists' Union, 1934.
  Photographs of works of art consist of drawings, lithographs, paintings, machine ornaments, set designs, and a costume by Lozowick. Also included is work by various American, European, and Russian artists. Negatives (both acetate and glass) and lantern slides of works of art were most likely used to illustrate writings and lectures.
  Miscellaneous subjects include Lozowick's studio, the Soviet Pavilion at the 1939 World's Fair in New York, and an unidentified Soviet exhibition installation.
  A few photographs are among the illustrations of artists at work, in their studios, galleries, etc., filed with Series 6, Printed Material.
  Negatives and lantern slides have not been scanned.
  This series is organized into 4 subseries:
  8.1: People
  8.2: Works of Art
  8.3: Miscellaneous Subjects
  8.4: Negatives and Lantern Slides
  - People, 1892-1971, 8.1:
    - Louis Lozowick, 1898-1971, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1140-1165)
    - Louis Lozowick and Family Members (father, wife Adele, son Lee), 1904-1945, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1166-1174)
    - Louis Lozowick with Others, 1918-1966, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1175-1194)
    - David Burliuk (?); Unidentified, 1920s, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1195-1199)
  - Works of Art, 1920s-1964, 8.2:
    - By Lozowick (Box 5, Reel 5899)
      - Drawings, 1924-1948, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1201-1209)
      - Lithographs, 1926-1964, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1210-1234)
      - Paintings, 1926-1963, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1235-1253)
      - Machine Ornaments, circa 1929 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1254-1267)
      - Set Designs for "Gas" by George Kaiser, Goodman Theatre, Chicago (drawing); Stage Set, 1926 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1268-1272)
      - Stage Set for Fashion Show; Costume Designed for Gilda Gray, Lord & Taylor Centennial, 1930 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1273-1277)
    - By Other Artists (Box 5, Reel 5899)
      - American, European, and Asian Art (A-Z, and Unidentified), n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1278-1342)
      - Russian Art (A-Z, and Unidentified), 1920s-1940s (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1343-1423)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1932-1962, 8.3:
    - Exhibition Installation, Soviet Union; Invitation to Opening of Lithograph Exhibition at Harry Isaacson Studio Fine Arts Gallery, 1932, 1962 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1425-1427)
    - Lozowick Studio, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1428-1430)
    - Soviet Pavilion, World's Fair, 1939 (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1431-1443)
    - Unidentified Landscape, n.d. (Box 5, Reel 5899, Frame 1444-1448)
  - Negatives and Lantern Slides, n.d. (Unfilmed), 8.4:
    - Acetate Negatives: American, European, and Russian Art; Jewish Interest, n.d. (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Glass Negatives: American, European, and Russian Art; Russian Architecture; Jewish Interest, n.d., (33 glass negatives in 4x6 card file) (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Lantern Slides: American, European, and Russian Art; Russian Architecture; Jewish Interest, n.d., (76 lantern slides in 4x6 card file) (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)